<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Overview</title>
  </properties>


  <body>
    <section name="Overview">
        <p>Beanoh, pronounced Bean-oh, is a simple open source way to verify your 
        Spring context. Teams that leverage Beanoh spend less time focusing on 
        configuring Spring and more time adding business value.</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Community">
        <p><a href="http://groups.google.com/group/beanoh">Beanoh Google Group (http://groups.google.com/group/beanoh)</a></p>
    </section>
    <section name="Features">
        <ol>
        	<li>Verify that all of your beans are wired correctly</li>
        	<li>Reconcile the beans marked with @Component in the classpath with the beans loaded in the Spring context</li>
        	<li>Prevent duplicate bean definition overwriting</li>
        </ol>
        <subsection name="Verify">
        	<p>Beanoh is a simple way to verify all of the beans in your Spring context.  
        	This lightweight tool supplies quick feedback without firing up your container. 
        	Beanoh provides three simple verification strategies:</p>
			<ol>
        		<li>The first strategy retrieves all of the beans in the Spring context 
        		and verifies that they are configured correctly.</li>
        		<li>The second strategy reconciles beans marked with 
        		org.springframework.stereotype.Component in the classpath with the beans 
        		available in the Spring context.</li>
        		<li>The final strategy verifes that bean definitions within your Spring 
        		context are unique.</li>
        	</ol>
			<p>Beanoh allows you to combine these strategies in a single test.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection name="Focus">
        	<p>Beanoh helps you focus on adding busines value.  Switching your focus between 
        	coding and configuring Spring is distracting.  While configuring Spring is 
        	absolutely necessary it should not be your primary focus.  Beanoh encourages 
        	you to focus on coding while it focuses on verifying your context.  Beanoh can 
        	help increase your productivity by encouraging you to focus on adding business 
        	value.</p>
        </subsection>
        <subsection name="Control">
       		<p>Beanoh uncovers Spring configuration errors and supplies timely information.  
       		This tool puts your team back in the driver's seat.  It identifies misconfigured 
       		beans, components that are not scanned by Spring, and duplicate bean definitions.  
       		Beanoh takes the mystery out of Spring.  You don't have to be a Spring guru to 
       		take control of your Spring context.  Beanoh does the heavy lifting and empowers 
       		you to take control of your Spring context.</p>
       	</subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="Building">
        <source> mvn clean install</source>
    </section>
    <section name="Using">
        <ol>
        	<li>Verify Spring wiring
<source>
  public class SomeTest extends BeanohTestCase {
	@Test
	public void testSomething() {
		assertContextLoading();
	}
  }
</source>

        	</li>
        	<li>Reconcile @Components
<source>
  public class SomeTest extends BeanohTestCase {

	@Test
	public void testSomething() {
		assertComponentsInContext("com.sourceallies");
	}
  }
</source>

        	</li>
        	<li>Ensure Unique Bean Definitions
<source>
  public class SomeTest extends BeanohTestCase {

	@Test
	public void testSomething() {
		assertUniqueBeanContextLoading();
	}
  }
</source>

        	</li>
        </ol>
    </section>
    <section name="Test Design">
        <p>Beanoh requires a test bootstrap Spring context file. BeanohTestCase 
        looks for a Spring context in the classpath with the same name as the 
        test plus "-BeanohContext.xml". For example 'com.sourceallies.anything.
        SomethingTest' will use 'com.sourceallies.anything.SomethingTest-BeanohContext.xml' 
        to bootstrap the Spring context. Add imports to this bootstrap context for 
        each of the context files that you wish to load. If you need to override 
        beans they must be added to this bootstrap context in order to not count 
        as a duplicate bean definition.</p>
    </section>
        <section name="Best Practices">
        <ol>
        	<li>Ignore classes annotated with @Component explicitly rather 
        	than by package. For example if you run 'assertComponentsInContext("com.sourceallies");' 
        	and it fails on a bean "com.sourceallies.something.Anything" in a 
        	dependent jar that you do not want to add to your context. Add 
        	'ignoreClassName("com.sourceallies.something.Anything");' to your 
        	test method instead of 'ignorePackages("com.sourceallies.something");'. 
        	The method 'ignorePackages' may ignore classes that you did not 
        	intend to ignore.</li>
        	<li>Override environment specific beans in the bootstrap context. 
        	For example JNDI references are environment specific and need to be overridden. 
        	<source><![CDATA[ <jee:jndi-lookup id="testBean" jndi-name="jdbc/test"/>]]></source>
        	A simple way to override this bean is to use Mockito to create mock beans. 
        	<source>
<![CDATA[  <bean id="testBean" class="org.mockito.Mockito" factory-method="mock">
      <constructor-arg value="com.something.Foo" />
  </bean>]]>
  		</source>
  		While this worked for most beans, I received errors when I wired 
  		up mock DataSources. Instead I used embedded databases to replace 
  		real DataSources. 
  		
        	<source><![CDATA[ <bean id="dataSource" parent="beanohDataSource"/>]]></source>
        	</li>
        	<li>
        	Setup system properties in a @BeforeClass method. 
        	<source>
<![CDATA[  @BeforeClass
public static void setupProperties(){
	System.setProperty("something", "someValue");
}]]>
  		</source>
        	</li>
        </ol>
    </section>
    <section name="License">
        <p>Copyright © 2011 Source Allies</p>
	<p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify 
	it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published 
	by the Free Software Foundation version 3.0.</p>
	<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but 
	WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY 
	or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public 
	License for more details.</p>
	<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public 
	License along with this library; if not, please visit 
	<a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl-3.0.txt">http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl-3.0.txt</a>.</p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>